<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Modules>
    <Module name="ModuleWindowsUpdateEnabled">
        <Name>Windows Updates</Name>
        <Priority>1</Priority>
        <Details>
            Having Windows Updates enabled is essential in keeping your system up to date and secure against the latest
            vulnerabilities.
            When a problem is found in Windows that might compromise your security, the vendor creates a patch delivered
            in the form of updates
            to secure your system against these vulnerabilities. When updates are disabled, you do not receive this
            patches.
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="disabled" score="0">
                Your Windows Updates are disabled, leaving your system vulnerable to the latest unpatched
                vulnerabilities.
                Consider
                <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/901037/how-to-enable-and-to-disable-microsoft-update">
                    re-enabling
                </a>
                your Windows Updates to receive security patches in the future.
            </Step>
            <Step result="enabled" score="100">
                Your Windows Updates are already enabled, there's nothing to fix here.
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>

    <Module name="ModulePasswordStorage">
        <Name>Safe Password Storage</Name>
        <Priority>3</Priority>
        <Details>
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="in-browser" score="0">
                Gordon Guan created a utility that steals all passwords that are saved using your browsers built-in
                password manager. Third-party password managers such as
                <a href="https://www.lastpass.com">LastPass</a>
                or
                <a href="http://keepass.info/">KeePass</a>
                offer better encryption and protection from such attacks.
            </Step>
            <Step result="not-disabled" score="100">
                Your Windows Updates are already enabled, there's nothing to fix here.
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>

    <Module name="ModuleAntivirusInstalled">
        <Name>Antivirus Software</Name>
        <Priority>1</Priority>
        <Details>
            With our world becoming increasingly technologically advanced, the online threats we are facing are becoming
            more intelligent everyday. With such advanced software trying to steal our data, we need to make sure we are
            up to speed with the latest security advancements.
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="no-antivirus" score="0">
                You have no antivirus software activated on your computer. With online threats being extremely difficult
                to detect for even the most experienced computer users, you are putting your computer in extreme danger.
                We recommend installing a free antivirus such as
                <a href="http://www.avg.com/us-en/homepage">AVG</a> because it stays up to date with the latest threats
                affecting your computer.
            </Step>

            <Step result="windows-defender" score="50">
                While you have Windows Defender activated, we recommend installing a free antivirus such as
                <a href="http://www.avg.com/us-en/homepage">AVG</a> because it stays up to date with the latest threats
                affecting your computer.
            </Step>

            <Step result="antivirus-activated" score="100">
                You have an active, up-to-date antivirus software, great!
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>

    <Module name="ModuleFirewallEnabled">
        <Name>Firewall</Name>
        <Priority>1</Priority>
        <Details>
            Firewalls allow you to communicate on the web while preventing intruders from accessing your data. Microsoft
            recommends that you "shouldn't turn off Windows Firewall unless you have another firewall turned on".
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="firewall-off" score="0">
                You have no active firewall on your computer! This is extremely dangerous and may lead to unauthorized
                access on your personal information from external users. We recommend that you turn your firewall on
                immediately! <a href="https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/instantanswers/c9955ad9-1239-4cb2-988c-
                982f851617ed/turn-windows-firewall-on-or-off">Here's how to do it.</a>
            </Step>
            <Step result="firewall-on" score="100">
                Your firewall is active and you are being protected from unauthorized access to your data!
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>

    <Module name="ModuleDriveEncrypted">
        <Name>Drive Encryption</Name>
        <Priority>3</Priority>
        <Details>
            Encrypting your drive protects your data in the case of your device being stolen or your data storage
            location being compromised. When you encrypt your drive, you prevent anyone from accessing any file on it,
            unless they know the password which you encrypted it with.
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="not-encrypted" score="0">
                While encrypting your hard drive provides countless improvements to the safety of your sensitive data,
                it is not for everyone. Before embarking on your encryption journey, read through a tutorial which walks
                you through the process.
                <a href="http://lifehacker.com/a-beginners-guide-to-encryption-what-it-is-and-how-to-1508196946">
                    Here's a good one.</a>
            </Step>
            <Step result="encrypted" score="100">
                Your OS drive is encrypted. This means your data is safe in the case of a hardware compromise.
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>

    <Module name="ModuleHomeNetworkEncryption">
        <Name>Network Encryption</Name>
        <Priority>2</Priority>
        <Details>
            When connecting to wireless networks, an important characteristic to look out for is the security of said network.
            Connecting to networks which are deemed "insecure" or "open" expose your network traffic to potential bad actors on the 
            same network, compromising your information privacy.
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="has-open" score="60">
                You have connected to at least one open network in the past. 
                Although this usually comes with little risk, be wary about carrying out sensitive transactions or transferring 
                private information across these networks.
            </Step>
            <Step result="no-open" score="100">
                Suprisingly, you seem to have never connected to an open or insecure network in your entire computer's life. Whether 
                paranoid, or this is just a new computer, your computer is significantly safer from using only secured networks.
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>

    <Module name="ModuleBackupsEnabled">
        <Name>Backup</Name>
        <Priority>2</Priority>
        <Details>
            You have a lot of important data, like your photos and documents, much of which you can't live without.
            That's why it's imperative that you make backups of this data.
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="backup-not-set" score="0">
                In the case of a drive failiure, data breach, or accidental deletion, you have no way to get your data
                back. We recommend creating a continuous backup schedule onto an external drive using Windows built-in
                tools. <a href="http://www.pcmag.com/article2/0,2817,2375207,00.asp">
                    Here's a step-by-step walk-through.</a>
            </Step>
            <Step result="backup-set" score="100">
                Your data is successfully being backed up onto an external drive. However, you still have to make sure
                the external drive is in a safe location and has it's own defence against external threats.
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>

    <Module name="ModuleUACEnabled">
        <Name>User Account Control Settings</Name>
        <Priority>3</Priority>
        <Details>
            Windows has a built-in technology called User Account Control (UAC), which prevents unauthorized changes to
            your computer by requiring an admin password before making changes above a certain impact threshold.
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="never-notify" score="0">
                With UAC disabled, applications don't need to be authorized in order to make changes to your computer
                such as modifying files on your drive. This setting is not recommended unless you are using it intently.
                <a href="https://articulate.com/support/article/how-to-turn-user-account-control-on-or-off-in-windows-10">
                    Here's how you could change your UAC setting to a safer one.</a>
            </Step>

            <Step result="sometimes-notify" score="50">
                Your UAC setting provides maximum security for any changes which apps try to make on your computer.
                However, the highest UAC level also asks for confirmation whenever you try to make changes to windows
                settings. This is a great safety feature to prevent you from accidentally making dangerous changes to
                Windows. <a href="https://articulate.com/support/article/how-to-turn-user-account-control-on-or-off-in-windows-10">
                    You could turn this feature on following this guide.</a>
            </Step>

            <Step result="always-notify" score="100">
                You have the highest level of protection for Windows. You will be asked to confirm before any
                significant changes to Windows occur.
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>

    <Module name="ModuleAutorunDisabled">
        <Name>Autorun</Name>
        <Priority>3</Priority>
        <Details>
            Autorun is a feature in Windows which allows for devices that you plug into your computer to automatically
            open and execute files. This opens up many vulnerabilities that people with malicious intent may exploit.
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="autorun-on" score="0">
                With Autorun turned on, your computer may be at risk to malicious external media which use Autorun to
                automatically run commands which infect your system. You could protect your computer using
                <a href="http://thetechhacker.com/2016/03/20/how-to-disable-the-autorun-feature-in-windows-10/">
                    this tutorial.</a>
            </Step>

            <Step result="autorun-off" score="100">
                The Autorun feature is turned off on your computer! This protects you when you are connecting external
                media to your computer.
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>

    <Module name="ModuleDNSServer">
        <Name>Using a Secure DNS</Name>
        <Priority>2</Priority>
        <Details>
            Domain Name System (DNS) is the technology that translates urls (such as www.google.com) into their
            respective IP addresses. Most people just use the DNS provided by their Internet Service Provider (ISP), but
            there are many third party options as well.
        </Details>
        <NextSteps>
            <Step result="default-dns" score="0">
                You are using the default DNS. Third-party DNS such as
                <a href="http://thetechhacker.com/2016/03/20/how-to-disable-the-autorun-feature-in-windows-10/">
                    Google's Public DNS</a>
                is always being developed and updated to the latest standards. This almost always results in faster
                performance, increased security, improved reliability, and additional features such as parental controls
                compared to your ISP's DNS.
            </Step>

            <Step result="third-party-dns" score="100">
                The Autorun feature is turned off on your computer! This protects you when you are connecting external
                media to your computer.
            </Step>
        </NextSteps>
    </Module>
  <Module name="ModuleSecurityPolicyScreenSaver">
    <Name>Screensaver Timeout</Name>
    <Priority>4</Priority>
    <!--<Category>CategorySecurityPolicy</Category>-->
    <Details>
      Having a reasonably short lockscreen timeout increases the likelihood that your computer is locked and safe when you are away 
      from it.
    </Details>
    <NextSteps>
      <Step result="screensaver-good" score="100">
        You have a good duration for your lockscreen timeout, ensuring your computer is locked when idle and out of use.
      </Step>
      <Step result="screensaver-long" score="50">
        Although you do have a lockscreen timeout setup, its delay is quite long, negating its usefulness. Shorten the length of your timeout. 
      </Step>
      <Step result="screensaver-none" score="0">
        You do not have a lockscreen timeout setup! Set one in your personalization settings to increase the security of your machine.
        <a href="http://www.windowscentral.com/how-extend-lock-screen-timeout-display-turn-windows-10"></a>
      </Step>
    </NextSteps>
  </Module>
</Modules>
